# ANTHONY ETIM

Address: Yale University, 10 Hilllhouse Avenue, New Haven, CT, 06511

Email: anthony.etim@yale.edu Webpage: <a href="https://anthonyedemetim.com/">https://anthonyedemetim.com/</a> Phone Number: +1 (215) 485-8250

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthony-etim/

## **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

My research interests lie in computer architecture and security, especially focusing on cloud infrastructures and the security of FPGA-accelerated cloud environments by evaluating and defending various types of side channels and covert channels, as well as how to enable secure multi-tenant Cloud FPGAs.

#### **EDUCATION**

Yale University, New Haven, CT

August 2021 – Present

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Research Assistant, Computer Architecture and Security (CAS) Lab.

Advisor: Prof. Jakub Szefer

**Villanova University,** Villanova, PA

August 2017 – May 2021

B.S. in Electrical Engineering,

Minors in Computer Science and Computer Engineering

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming:** C++, C, JavaScript, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, Java, Python, SQL, VHDL, Verilog/ System Verilog, Haskell

Tools: AWS tools, Docker, Xilinx Vivado/ISE, Quartus, Jupyter Notebook

Technological Devices: Raspberry Pi, Arduino

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Anthony Etim, Shanquan Tian, and Jakub Szefer. "Extending FPGA Information Leaks with Trojan Phantom Circuits". Accepted by the IEEE International Symposium on Secure and Private Execution Environment Design (SEED), 2024.
- Theodoros Trochatos, Anthony Etim, and Jakub Szefer. "Covert-channels in FPGA-enabled SmartSSDs". Accepted by the 22nd International Conference on Field-Programmable Technology (FPT), 2023 Journal Track at ACM Transactions on Reconfigurable Technology and System (TRETS).

#### RESEARCH EXPRIENCE

Yale University, Graduate Researcher, New Haven, CT

August 2021 – Present

• Exploring information leaks and using Ring Oscillators (ROs) and Time to Digital Converters (TDCs) to sense voltage and thermal changes in FPGA-accelerated cloud environments.

**Villanova University,** *Undergraduate Researcher*, Villanova, PA

Fall 2020 – Spring 2021

• Developed a deep neural network to achieve a secrecy capacity for efficient, reliable and secure transmission of information.

#### Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Fall 2020

- Used Matrix Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) technique to optimize the deep neural network (DNN) on the AVNET Ultra96-V2 FPGA development board.
- Evaluated the performance, accuracy, and energy consumption of the optimized system.

## Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Spring 2020

- Estimated the added value and future costs of coordinated economics dispatch in Central America through the electrical system load.
- Trained the neural network to forecast the electrical system load.

# Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Summer 2019

- Collaborated with a team of 3 in conjunction with L3 Harris in the creation of an efficient food purchasing and tracking system for dining services to reduce food waste.
- Developed software system that is simple to populate and used to track purchased quantities and consumption to reduce waste significantly.
- Filed a provisional patent for the software system.

## Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

March 2018 – May 2019

- Conducted research on the development of the flow network modeling tool Villanova Thermodynamic Analysis of Systems (VTAS), which models the energy flows throughout a data center.
- Upgraded the Graphical User Interface (GUI) for the Villanova Thermodynamic Analysis of Systems (VTAS) data center flow network modeling tool.
- Developed the GUI Interface for the VTAS electrical system layout.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Electrical Engineering Intern, National Grid, Albany, NY, Remote

Summer 2020

- Collaborated with a team of 4 engineers to help reorganize and plan the grid network using various tools.
- Modelled data to fit various design requirements and constraints of the power system.
- Assisted in the management and creation of a SharePoint Setting Repository for the handoff of smart control settings to the field device engineers.
- Collaborated with other engineers to build a database of DMX and control house plans for the grid network.

## Web Developer Intern, Kumba Africa, Philadelphia, PA

Summer 2018

- Built reusable code to be utilized in other projects, effectively streamlining spending.
- Contributed back-end experience and collaborated on APIs.
- Collaborated on the design and development on a team of 4 of client and server database applications.
- Analyzed project requirements to find bugs and eliminate issues within a timely manner.

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• **Teaching Fellow**, Yale University, New Haven, CT Introduction to Computer Engineering (EENG 201)

Spring 2023

• **Teaching Fellow,** Yale University, New Haven, CT Introduction to Electronics (EENG 200)

Fall 2022

#### **POSTERS**

- Oct. 2019. Feastimate. Future of Packaging Consortium, Villanova University, PA
- April 2019. Improving the user interface of Data center modeling Software. (Project #1) Center for Energy-Smart Electronic Systems, Industrial Advisory Board Meeting at Binghamton University, NY.
- Oct. 2018. Improving the user interface of Data center modeling Software. (Project #1) Center for Energy-Smart Electronic Systems, Industrial Advisory Board Meeting at Villanova University, PA.
- Sep. 2018. Improving the user interface of Data center modeling Software. Undergraduate Research Symposium at Villanova University, PA.

#### **SERVICE**

• Yale Cloud Computing and FPGA Security Symposium (CCFS) 2022, Co-organizer
November 2022

• Yale Grad Society of Women Engineers, Undergrad Liaison Co-chair Fall 2022 - Present

## **LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

**Tau Beta Pi,** National Engineering Honor Society, Villanova Chapter, Vice-President

March 2020-May 2021

- Planned and conducted various professional events for the chapter's members such as the initiation information session for new members.
- Helped in the advancement of the technical and professional education of the active members by connecting them with various alumni.

## Villanova Engineering Student Council, Co-Chair

September 2019- May 2021

• Planned events for the College of Engineering and acted as a bridge between the students and faculty.

## National Society of Black Engineers, Senator

August 2017-September 2018

• Represented Villanova chapter at the 2017 Fall Regional Conference in Greensboro, NC.

## **SELECTED HONORS AND AWARDS**

• Yale New Student Fellowship

September 2021

• Dean's Award for Academic Excellence

May 2021

• Dean's Award for Meritorious Service

May 2021

• Dean's List

**Every Semester** 

• Klingler Unitas Prize,

April 2020

Villanova Student Entrepreneurship Competition

- Klingler Unitas Prize, Villanova Student Entrepreneurship Competition
- Tau Beta Pi, the National Engineering Honor Society, Selected based on academic ranking 1/8th of the junior class.

Spring 2020

April 2019